Guide to the Edward Miller scores and sheet music ARCH163
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Edward Miller scores and sheet music
1952-2002, undated
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Miller, Edward J. (Edward Jay), 1930-2013
ARCH163
0.75 Linear Feet (4 containers)
The collection contains musical arrangements and compositions of Edward Miller from 1952-2002.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Edward Miller was born August 4, 1930 to Sophia and Samuel Miller in Miami, Florida. At ten years old, he learned to play music starting with the trumpet and then later moved to valve trombone and baritone horn when he started to wear braces. By age sixteen, he had started playing in a professional jazz band. He earned a bachelor's of music degree from the University of Miami and in 1955 earned his Master of music degree in composition from the Hartt College of Music under the guidance of Arnold Franchetti and Isadore Freed. In 1959, he became a faculty member of the Hartt College of Music and taught for twelve years before leaving in 1971 for Oberlin College where he taught until his retirement in 1998. In 2005, Miller relocated to New Mexico with his wife Judi Miller until he passed away on August 31, 2013.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of scores and sheet music composed and arranged by Edward Miller while he was a faculty member of the Hartt College of Music and Oberlin College.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series: I. Compositions, II. Arrangements.
Scores; Sheet music
- Compositions, 1952-2002, undated
  Scope and Contents
  The music scores and sheet music in this series were composed by Edward Miller.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically by song title.
  - Anacrusis, 1975 Sep (Box Shared Oversized 1)
  - Anti-Heroic Amalgam, 1969 Jan (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Around, 1973 Feb (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Beyond the Wheel, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cascades, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Concerto for Violin, Piano, and Chamber Orchestra, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
  - Conquest, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Criss Cross, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dialoque, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Duo Concertante, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fantasy Concerto, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Five Short Pieces, 1967 Jan (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Folly Stone, 1966 Mar (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Going Home, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Images From the Eye of a Dolphin, 1989 Jan (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Kaleido Scope, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - La Mi La Sol, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - A Lullaby For Ben, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mists and Waters, 1996 Nov (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Percussion Quintet, 1972 Dec (Box Shared Oversized 1)
  - Piano Trio, 1984 Mar (Box Shared Oversized 1)
  - Piece for Clarinet and Tape, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Playing The Odds, 1980 (Box Shared Oversized 1)
  - Serenade, 1981 Jul (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Seven Sides of a Crystal, 1983 (Box Shared Oversized 1)
  - Six Cannons, 1963 Mar, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Song for Recorder or Flute, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Three Pieces for Band, 1964 Feb (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Three Songs, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10, Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Three Trios, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Two Pieces, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Two Settings, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Vocal Pieces, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Woodwind Quantet, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Young God: A Vaudeville, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Arrangements, 1984-1996, undated
  The series contains music scores and sheet music arranged by Edward Miller.
  - Don't Blame Me, 1984 Jan (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - I'll be Seeing You, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - I'll Remember April, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Night and Day, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Over the Rainbow, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Red, Red Robin, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Star Dust, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Stella by Starlight, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Swinging on a Star, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - You Stepped Out of a Dream, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)